¶ Gems ¶
¶ We'll always save the day ¶
Steven: ¶ And if you think
we can't, we'll ¶
¶ Always find a way ¶
¶ That's why the people ¶
¶ Of this world ¶
¶ Believe in ¶
¶ Garnet ¶
Amethyst: ¶ Amethyst ¶
Pearl: ¶ And Pearl ¶
And Steven!
[ Insects buzz ]
你刚刚看到了吗？
Did you see that?
咣当！嘭的一下！
Wapoosh!
Just wapoosh!
很棒啊，紫晶
That's great, Amethyst.
你进步的真快
You're getting so fast.
不！刚才那下糟透了！
No! This is worse!
今天早上的时候它还发出嗖的声音！
This morning,
it was like wsshh!
嗖的一下！快极了，嗖，嗖嗖！
Just wsshh! Superfast,
like wsshh, wsshh!
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
我想你今天
I think this is why
休息一下会比较好
a day off would be good for you.
你不能总是想着
You should take a break
怎么做掉铁石英
from obsessing over Jasper.
呃，你确定我们必须今天去那里？
Ugh, are you sure we have to do this now?
当然！
Yes!
拜访一下橄榄石和青金石会很有趣的！
Visiting Peridot and Lapis will be so much fun!
是啊，一说到“有趣”，我马上能联想到青金石
Yeah, 'cause when I think "fun," I think Lapis.
不知道她们最近在做什么
I wonder
what they're up to.
可能已经把对方都逼疯了吧
Maybe they drove each other crazy
然后一把火把谷仓烧了
and burnt the barn down.
喔啊
Whoa.
她们的确对谷仓做了不少改动
They sure did something to the barn.
但是，波莱特，我需要你.
But, Paulette, I need you.
哦，快放手吧，佩西
Oh, get over it,Percy.
换个人做友谊手环吧
Go make another friendship bracelet.
可不是嘛
Seriously.
青金石，橄榄石，嗨！
Lapis, Peridot, hi!
史蒂文！
Steven!
又见面真是太好了！
It's so good to see you again!
我也是，青金石
You, too, Lapis.
紫晶！
Amethyst!
你今天看上去有所不同啊
Something looks different about you.
怎么不同？
Like what?
和上次见面时比
Have you grown taller
你好像长高了？
since the last timeI saw you?
没，还很矮
Nope, still short.
[ Laughing ]
不用谢
You're welcome.
开玩笑啦
For the joke.
哇哦，你们看上去真不错
Wow. You guys
are looking good.
我超喜欢你们对谷仓的改动
And I love what you did to the barn.
嗷，我知道它很棒
Aw, I know.
但等等，等等！
But wait, wait!
你们一定要看看谷仓的内部！
You guys have to see the inside!
青金石，带我们飞进去！
Lapis, fly us in!
不
No.
欢迎来的我们母星外的家
Welcome to our home away from Homeworld.
喔啊！
Whoa!
你们把墙壁做成了水族箱！
You made the wall
an aquarium!
呃呃呃！
Eww!
你们刻意做的这些装修？
You did all this stuff on purpose?
我是说，简直像你们把东西随便扔一堆
Like, you didn't just knock over a bunch
然后说“呃，以后再收拾”
of paint cans and go,"Enh, just leave it"?
哦不，整个谷仓的装修都是非常有意义的
Oh, no. This was all very intentional.
是这样的，当时我有个主意：既然我们可以用声音创作音乐
You see, I had this idea:"What if we made music,
那为什么不可以用物体创作呢？
but, instead of sounds,we used things?"
真是蠢透了
That's dumb.
伙计们，这是艺术！
Guys, that's art!
艺术？
Art?
听上去好蠢！
That sounds ridiculous!
我们一直都管这些东西叫“咪嗼”
I've been calling it meep morp.
给你看看我们的嗼嗼
Let us show you
our morps.
这个作品叫“哇，谢谢”
This piece is called Wow, Thanks.
它表达了人们因为沟通的隔阂而挣扎
It represents the struggles of intercommunication.
录音带是将我们两人的经历
The tape is the ribbon that binds
连结在一起的桥梁
our experienceon Earth together.
它没什么实用意义
It has no functional purpose.
只是能让我心里难受而已
It just makes me feel bad.
这是我的咪嗼
Here's my meep morp.
它是个球棒
This is a baseball bat.
它让我想起了玩棒球的时光
It reminds me of when I played baseball.
这是史蒂文给我的树叶
This is the leaf Steven gave me.
它让我想起…史蒂文给了我一片树叶
It reminds me of the time Steven...gave me a leaf.
嘿，对啊，我也记得！
Hey, yeah, it reminds me of that, too!
我感觉被囚禁了
I just feel trapped.
这是表达那几千年
Is this one about the thousands of years
你被困在镜子中的事吗？
you spent trapped in a mirror?
不
No.
我只是很喜欢那个电视剧
I just really like that show.
哦，紫晶，你会爱死这个的.
Oh, Amethyst,you'll love this one.
瞧瞧
Check it out.
这是一堆马桶？
They're toilets?
没错！
Right!
真不敢想我还能有什么好点子
What will I think of next?!
这代表了我被关在
This represents the time I spent imprisoned
你卫生间里的那段时光，史蒂文
in your bathroom, Steven.
我管它叫“有人使用”
I call it Occupied.
这是一部合作品
It's a collaborative piece.
真是太精彩了
It's amazing.
我不明白
I don't get it.
你不需要明白啊
What's there to get?
是水！
It's water!
从马桶里喷出来的水！
Shooting out of toilets!
我在家里也能看到啊
I can see that at home.
好吧，我知道你觉得这挺没意思的
All right. I see you're not impressed.
但这个——别激动
But this -- hold on.
它——这就是我们一直在等的压轴戏
This -- this is what we've all been waiting for.
加上我控制金属的能力
With the power of my metal abilities,
它会让你们惊得裙子都飞走的！
I will impress the shirts right off of you!
嗒哒！
Ta-da!
这是个单石乐队！
It's a one-Gem metal band.
一呀，二呀，三呀，开始…
One, a-two, a-three, and...
嘛，我就练习了这么多
Welp, that's as far as I've practiced that.
你为什么不试试一次只用一个乐器呢？
Why don't you try one thing at a time?
因为我们有客人啊，青金石
Because we have guests, Lapis,
我们得让客人们高兴！
guests who must be impressed!
唔
Hmm.
我们可以一起表演
We can try it together.
对啊
Yeah.
¶
这难道不是很棒吗？
Isn't this great?
不
No.
瞧瞧她们一直在做这么酷的东西
Look at all this cool stuff they're doing.
这些东西算什么！
This is all nothing!
她们一直都在谷仓里玩破烂
They've been out here playing with garbage.
但你不是很喜欢玩破烂吗？
But you love playing with garbage.
早就不玩了
Not anymore.
谁有时间浪费在这些破烂上？！铁石英还在外面游荡呢？！
Who has time for any that when Jasper is out there?!
¶
啊，紫晶
Ah, Amethyst,
我，呃，尽量别在这里
I, uh, try not to use the J-word
随便说铁某的名字
so loosely around here.
我要去做点更有意义的事了
[sigh] I'm gonna go do
something useful.
先别管你的名字了--你还有一场架要干呢
Forget your name --you've got a fight to win!
哇哦，紫晶看上去完全无法理解嗼嗼！
Wow, Amethyst doesn't seem to understand morps at all!
我想一个玫瑰石英和一个紫水晶
I think a rose quartz and an amethyst...
不，她是因为其他原因不高兴的
No, it's something else:
紫晶发现
Amethyst found out
在一起就是
…make a...
她本应该是铁石英那样高大的战士
she's supposed to be just like Jasper.
咩？
Meh?
前几天她被铁石英的打得惨败
Jasper took her down in a fight and, now,
烟晶
...Smoky Quartz.
这些天她一直想着怎样打回去
she's obsessed with getting a rematch,
你们水晶宝石难道现在只懂融合这招吗
Is fusion the only trick you crystal gems know?
来证明她足够好
to prove she's good enough.
唔
Hmm.
嘛我懂的招式还真不少
I've got plenty of tricks.
见过【前抛】没有
Ever see sink the dink?
紫晶，小晶晶，紫老大
Amethyst,Ams, Big A.
你比铁石英强太多了
You are way better than Jasper.
什么？
What?
哦
Oh.
你都告诉她什么了？
What did you tell her?
我，呃…
I, uh...
你这是想啥呢，干嘛把自己跟铁石英比？
What are you even doing,comparing yourself to her?
哦紫晶，这太荒谬了
Oh, Amethyst,that's ridiculous.
我应该叫你荒谬晶
I should call you Ridiculousthyst.
哈！呀！
Hah! Yah!
不
No!
我是认真的，紫晶和铁石英
I mean, seriously,Amethyst and Jasper
是两种完全不同的石英
are two completely different Quartzes.
我的军队
My army!
当然，你们俩都来自地球
Sure, you're both from Earth,
哈糊你一脸
Take that!
但你们的出生地有天壤之别
but your Kindergartens are radically different.
再吃我这招
Then take this!
啥？
What?
等—等等，什么？！
Hold --Hold on. What?!
我们都是在地球出生的？
We're both from Earth?
嘛，对呀
Well, sure.
紫晶，你来自主宝宝基地
Amethyst, you're from the Prime Kindergarten,
在第五区
in Facet 5.
而她来自副宝宝基地，在第九区
She's from the Beta Kindergarten, in Facet 9.
你们去过那个地方吗？
Have you seen that place?
没有！
No!
啊 这么快就要离开啦
Aw. Leaving so soon?
哦，好吧，你们应该去看看，这样你就能明白
Oh. Well, maybe you should,so you could see
其他的宝石是怎么做出来的的
how the other half was made.
粗制滥造！
Poorly!
我不会再败在融合上了
I will not be beaten by another fusion!
不，认真的，咱们走吧
No, seriously.Let's go.
看完你就该释怀了吧
You'll get a kick out of this.
什么鬼
What the...
那是你的个人问题，波莱特
That's your problem,Paulette.
是你任由自己变成舠一族的
You let yourself become the kayak race.
太凄凉了
Cold.
呃，给我一秒钟
Um, just one second.
我想确认一下青金石一个人没问题
I want to check and make sure Lapis is okay.
等等
Hold on.
嘿，青金石！你没问题吧？？！
Hey, Lapis!
Are you okay-y-y?!
我还真有个可以把你干飞的招
I've got a move that will really blow you away.
没问题！
Yeah!
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
确定！
Yeah!
我要走了，但我很快就会回来！
I'm leavin',but I'll be back!
好！
Okay!
你需要什么东西吗？！
Do you need anything?!
你不喜欢也没关系
It's cool if you don't like it.
不需要！
No!
你现在看的是第几季？！
What season is that?!
我已经准备了三个大风扇啦
I've already got three huge fans.
第三季！
3!
橄榄石，走吧
Peridot, let's go.
哦对，好
Okay, yeah.
工作时间
Business time.
你知道要把它放到哪里的！
You know what to do with this!
我们只要坚持在一起…就可以打败她们
We could beat them... if we stay together.
咱们到了，铁石英的出生地，副宝宝基地
Here we are, Jasper's origin:the Beta Kindergarten.
是我的问题吗？
Am I underwhelmed?
这里亮得刺眼
It's pretty bright out here.
全是红色的
It's red.
确实
No kidding.
干的漂亮 小烟
Great job, Smoky.
噢 谢谢 谢了 小烟
Oh, thank you, thank you, Smoky.
红砂岩！哈！
Red sandstone! Ha!
这材料不能更差！
This is what I'm talking about.
这地方还没被炸烂也是很幸运
We're lucky this place hasn't blown away.
果然只能算“副”，对不对？
Beta, am I right?
跟我融合的人从来没有愿意留下的
Nobody I fuse with ever wants to stay.
这是什么数学玩笑吗？
That's a math joke,right?
快来吧，这里还会更糟的
Come on.It get's worse.
我是说，这个地方成长环境还好
I mean, this place has got the right
我想也确实难得
growing conditions,
in a pinch,
但它面积太小了！
I guess,
but it's too small!
这里完全就是赶工做出来的
It was obviously a total rush job.
赶工？
A rush job?
内战进行到一半的时候
Halfway through the rebellion,
母星急于在地球上
Homeworld scrambled to generate
制造出更多的士兵
extra soldierson the ground.
瞧瞧这个:这些洞都没排成直线！
Look at this: the holes don't even line up!
噫 超恶心啦
Ew! That's disgusting.
是堕转
It's corruption.
就好像他们只是
It's like they just
随随便便找个地方打个孔
threw injectors down wherever.
哦，再看这个
Oh, and that one?
史蒂文 小心啊
Steven, be careful.
这个玛瑙是斜着出来的
This Carnelian came out sideways.
但是我不能眼睁睁地看着它发生
But this just happened.
她只能斜着出来！
How could she not?
也许我可以做些什么
Maybe I can do something.
这些岩壁都是弯的！
The walls are curved!
铁石英 没事的
Jasper, it's okay.
简直可笑
What a joke.
我就在这里
I'm here.
惊了，难以置信
Man, I-I had no idea.
玫瑰
Rose.
跟你讲，这真的会让感谢
I tell you, it really makes you appreciate
我不是玫瑰 我是史蒂文
I'm not Rose. I'm Steven.
主宝宝基地的，紫晶
the Prime Kindergarten,
Amethyst.
我现在只想试着治愈你
I just want to try and heal you.
你的宝宝基地很有讲究的
Your Kindergarten
was so thought-through.
是，你可能的确在地下花的时间比较长
Sure, you might've spent
extra time in the ground,
史蒂文
Steven!
但除了这点你其他的先天条件都很优秀
but everything else
is stacked in your favor:
不错的地点，不错的出生洞穴
great location,great holes,
均匀的空间分配，连贯的洞穴尺寸
even spacing,consistent depth.
专业宝宝基地工程师才做得好
A real Kindergartener gets it right.
什么 别冲动
What? Stop.
我现在知道你的把戏了
I see how you do it now, Rose.
这个注射器发生了什么？
What happened to this injector?
你在宝石人失去价值后再去收她们入伙
You want gems after they're worthless.
理想情况下，洞穴该是垂直的
What you want to see is a vertical alignment;
出口应该呈现出清晰的轮廓，而不是斜角
no angle in the exit;a clean, strong silhouette.
你一直等到她们失败才动手
You wait until after they've lost.
这些洞穴里没有一个达成了指标！
None of these holes come close!
因为当你到了最倒霉的时候
Because when you're at the bottom,
这个呢？
What about that one?
就会顺从于从任何人
you'll follow anyone.
这会减轻你的挫败感
That makes you feel like less of a failure.
铁石英
Jasper.
这是铁石英的洞穴？
This is Jasper's hole?
它可真大！
It's huge!
哦，拜托
Oh, come on.
呃 就看看这个家伙
Ugh. Just look at this one.
我们都知道她挺高的
We already know she's tall.
你剥夺了她的一切 --
You've stripped her of everything --
我们来近距离瞧一瞧它
Let's take a closer look.
她的扩增肢，她的地位，她的尊严
her limb enhancers, her status, her dignity.
一个宝宝基地工程师最明白——
A Kindergartener can tell a lot --
啊！怎样通过洞穴的出口观察——
Anh! -- about a Gem's makeup and --
呃！——宝石的构成和缺陷
Uh! -- flaws by their exit marks.
我还有一样呢
I still have one of those things.
你怎么可以站在玫瑰石英那边
How can you side with Rose Quartz?
史蒂文
Steven.
哦
Oh.
为什么
Why?
啊！
Ah!
为什么要保护这个没用的空壳行星
Why protect this useless shell of a planet?
呜呼！
Oof!
谢了
Thanks.
啊！
Agh!
它不是一个空壳
It's not a shell.
你瞧，问题在——
You see,the problem here --
这里还有数不胜数的生命
There's so much life.
等等. 哦，等下，呃
Wait.Oh, wait. Oh.
生活 --这就是我在这里做的事啊
Living here -- that's what I'm doing!
不，唔…
No, um...
我生活在这里
I'm living here.
现在我每时每刻都在了解自己未发掘的潜能
I've been learning new things about myself all the time,
这个地方——
Now this part --
唔
Hmm.
但是呢，如果你用脚步来测量
There's this thing where,if you count the steps
比如现在我可以让金属都顺从我的旨意
like how I can make metal do my bidding.
到底的距离，就能——
to the back, I can --
重点是…
The point being...
地球可以给你自由
Earth can set you free.
怎么了？
What is it?
她的洞里连摩擦融化石头的痕迹都有
She's even got frictional rock melt.
地球…就是一个监牢
Earth...is a prison.
从洞口直到洞底都是玻璃的
It's glass all the way to the back.
我之所以可以离开是因为我远远优于这个鬼地方
I got out because I'm better than this place.
事实上，我，呃…
Actually, I, uh...
从来没见过这么完美的洞穴
I've never seen an exit hole this perfect.
情况在恶化
It's getting worse.
我回来就是为了结果你们
I only came back to finish you off.
惹
Ugh.
所以她真的比我好
So it is true.
尽量不要动
Try not to move.
紫晶，这一点都不重要
Amethyst,that doesn't matter.
你休想操控我 玫瑰石英
You can't manipulate me, Rose Quartz.
你是谁不取决于你来自哪里
Who you are isn't about where you came from;
取决于你想成为什么！
it's who you want to be!
我-我不是想操控你
I-I'm not manipulating.
取决于你努力的方向
It's what you've worked hard for.
我只是想帮忙
I'm -- I'm trying to help.
取决于你所重视的事物. 这才是重要的
It's what you care about.That's what really matters.
帮忙
Help?
Help?!
对
Yeah.
自我从这地壳破土而出
I've been fighting
你说的对！
Yeah, you're right!
我就一直在战斗
from the second I broke free of the Earth's crust
-对！-没错！
-Yeah!-Yeah!
只因你对我的殖民地做的事
because of what you did to my colony,
取决于我想要成为什么
It's about who I wanna be.
-没错！-没错！
-Yeah!-Yeah!
而我想成为那个宝石
And I wanna be the Gem
只因你对我的星球所做的事
because of what you did to my planet,
那个把铁石英打的满地找牙的宝石！
that beats Jasper into the dirt!
只因你对我的钻石所做的事
because of what you did to my diamond!
-没错！什么？！
-Yeah!-Huh?
等等，别！不要和她打！
Wait, no!Don't fight her!
我 --你说黄钻？
I -- Yellow Diamond?
你还不明白吗？
Are you not seeing this?
她是一个终极的石英战士
She's the ultimate Quartz!
我的钻石！
My diamond!
我就要这么做，没错，不只是为了我自己
I'm doin' it, yeah,and not just for me,
你的钻石！
Your diamond!
为了所有其他在这里出生的家伙们
for all the weird holes out here,
粉红钻石！
Pink diamond!
比如这个伙计，还有这个小瘦子
like this guy,and skinny up there,
还有——还有这个乱七八糟的家伙！
and -- and --and this mess!
紫晶，这是——
Amethyst, that's --
对，哈！我打赌她肯定挺厉害的
Yeah, ha!I bet she was great.
不不不，等等
No.No, no, no, hold on.
有什么地方不对
Something's really wrong here.
这些痕迹是新的
These marks are new.
这个洞穴是最近才被挖开的
This hole's been dug out, recently.
会不会是土拨鼠干的？
Maybe it was a prairie dog?
超大的一只？
A...really big one?
不用谢哈
You're welcome.
唔
Hmm.
还有更多！
There's more!
喔啊
Whoa.
这些已经不是出口洞穴了
These aren't exit holes anymore.
来吧 老姐
Come here, sis.
那他们是用来干嘛的？
Then what are they?
啊！
Aah!
史蒂文！
Steven!
宝石怪物，被囚禁的？
Corrupted Gems,in cages?
当我们回到谷仓后
When we get to the barn,
我要做个巨型金属溜溜球
I'm building a giant metal yo-yo.
为什么？！
Why?!
谁会想要这么做？！
Who would do this?!
紫晶 史蒂文 到时候你们要给我用它玩玩抛接
Amethyst, Steven, you'll have to catch and throw it for me.
就是她
That's who.
接下来的 大概一个月 我都不想做任何事了
I don't want to do anything for, like, a month.
铁石英
Jasper.
铁石英！
Jasper!
她在干嘛呢？
What is she doing?
她最近一直在收集宝石怪物
She's been collecting monsters.
安静！
Pipe down!
你们现在开始要服从我的命令！
You take orders from me now!
你曾经也是颗石英，不是吗？
You used to be a quartz, too,didn't you?
在你身上发生了什么？
What happened to you?
呃！肮脏
Ugh!Disgraceful.
不敢相信我居然收下你这种怪物做手下！
I can't believe I've resorted to recruiting you freaks!
你和水晶战士中的那个矮子一样糟糕
You're almost as bad as that crystal runt.
瞧瞧你
Just look at you.
这个星球毁掉了一切
This planet ruins everything.
好吧，除了我
Well except for me.
我们应该回神庙里叫上其他人
We should go back to the temple and grab reinforcements.
对，这是个好主意
Yeah,that's a good idea.
紫晶？
Amethyst?
紫晶！
Amethyst!
我永远不会让这颗星球像扭曲你这样毁掉我
I'll never let this planet twist me like it twisted you.
你的脆弱让母星蒙羞
Your weakness embarrasses Homeworld.
你的痛苦都是你自找的
You suffer because it's what you deserve.
我们身上发生的都理所应当
We all only get what we deserve.
对不对，紫晶？
Right, Amethyst?
哈？
Huh?
你来这里做什么，矮子？
What do you want,runt?
你要再次挑战我？
You here for a rematch?
我是来打败你的！
I'm here to win!
你出场的瞬间，已经注定会输了
You were fated to lose --the moment you came out wrong.
你胡说！
That's not true!
玫瑰，果不其然
Rose.Of course.
你的走狗在你也不会太远的
Your lackeys never stray far.
当然他们也不会离开你的
And why would they?
因为其他任何地方他们都没有立足之处了！
They have no place in this or any world!
你是什么意思？
What do you mean?
每个宝石都是为了某种目的而制造出的——
Every gem is made for a purpose --
为了服侍钻石的圣旨
to serve the order of the diamonds.
那些无法完成钻石命令的必须被清除！
Those who cannot fit inside this order must be purged!
出生时畸形的体态
To come out misshapen,
按照自己意愿胡乱变形
to reshape yourself outside your purpose,
保护这个无药可救，没用的星球
and to defend this ruined,worthless planet
这些都是耻辱！
is a disgrace!
这颗星球也没那么糟
This planet isn't all bad.
你在这儿干嘛呢？
What are you doing here?
我…
I...
我现在也是个水晶战士了！
I'm a crystal gem now!
我不怕你！
I'm not afraid of you!
我现在有金属能力了！
I've got metal powers!
你瞧着吧！
I'll show you!
啊啊老天
Aw, geez.
等等
In a moment.
还有人有要说的吗？
Anyone else got something to say?
不！没有别人了
No!It's just us.
呃！你们！
Ugh!You guys!
-哈？！-别来凑热闹了！
-Huh?!-Stay out of this!
紫晶！
Amethyst!
这是咱俩间的事，铁石英——
It's just you and me,Jasper --
一对一！
one on one!
上，紫晶！
Go, Amethyst!
现在谁是矮子了？
Who's the runt now?
你准备好了？
You ready for more?
还——还有别的招数呢
Th-- There's more where that came from.
啊哦
-Uh-oh.
哈？
Huh?
结束了吗？
Is it sinking in yet?
你是认真的吗？！
Are you serious?!
紫晶！
Amethyst!
你从未有过机会
You never had a chance.
¶
抬头！
Heads up!
-哈？-哈？
-Huh?-Huh?
史蒂文，我赢不了
Steven I can't win.
无论我做什么，无论我多么努力
No matter what I do,no matter how hard I work,
她生来完美，我生来卑微
she came out right,and I came out wrong.
这是铁石英认为的
That's just what Jasper thinks.
只有她觉得你本应该像她一样
She's the only one who thinks you should be like her.
-但是-不要再试图变得和铁石英一样了
-But -Stop trying to be like Jasper.
你和铁石英完全不同！
You're nothing like Jasper!
你更像我——
You're like me --
因为我们都是这样格格不入
because we're both not like anybody!
是啊，这是挺糟糕的
And, yeah, it sucks.
但至少我还有你
But at least I've got you.
你也有我
And you've got me.
所以不要再抛下我一个人战斗了
So stop leaving me out of this.
最糟的宝石总得呆在一起不是吗？
Us worst gems stick together right?
这也是为什么我们是最棒的
That's why we're the best.
¶
多么美好的一天！
What a beautiful day!w
哈?你是谁？
Huh?!Who are you supposed to be?
哦对啊，我现在是谁来着?
Oh, yeah!Who am I now?
我想紫晶应该知道我是谁
I feel like Amethyst knows this.